<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Space Cybersegurity on</title><link>/categories/space-cybersegurity/</link><description>Recent content in Space Cybersegurity on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/categories/space-cybersegurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From MITRE ATT&amp;CK to SPARTA: A Unified Attack Flow for Space Systems</title><link>/blog/from-mitre-attck-to-sparta-a-unified-attack-flow-for-space-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/from-mitre-attck-to-sparta-a-unified-attack-flow-for-space-systems/</guid><description>One of the most powerful aspects of cybersecurity research is the ability to extend and adapt existing tools to cover new domains. While the Attack Flow Builder from MITRE was originally designed to visualize and model cyber operations based on the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK framework, I needed to go a step further for my research in space cybersecurity.
The challenge: how to integrate SPARTA (a cybersecurity framework for space systems) into the Attack Flow Builder so that we can model attacks not only in traditional IT/OT contexts, but also in the space domain.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from the Viasat Cyberattack: A SPARTA Framework Analysis</title><link>/blog/lessons-from-the-viasat-cyberattack-a-sparta-framework-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/lessons-from-the-viasat-cyberattack-a-sparta-framework-analysis/</guid><description>In February 2022, one of the most notable cyber incidents in the space sector took place: the Viasat KA-SAT cyberattack. This event disrupted satellite communications across Europe, affecting both civilian and military users. For the cybersecurity and space communities, the incident stands as a turning point, highlighting how vulnerable the ground and user segments of space systems can be when targeted with coordinated cyber operations.
In this post, I’ll walk through a simplified analysis of the attack using the SPARTA framework, which is specifically designed for threats against space systems.</description></item></channel></rss>